Don't take this the wrong way, but it's very
likely that you're using Google
Yemini incorrectly.  If you use Yemini as a simple
chat app, you're missing out on 80% of its
power.  And someone will ask, "But
David, why do you say that if I use it
every day?"  Because it has a function that you've
probably only glanced at, and you're
definitely not taking full advantage of its
potential.  I'm talking about the
canvas tool.  This
practically gives your Gemini chat superpowers
and completely changes the way we
can use this model.
With this canvas function, it not only
responds to flat context, but it also
allows you to build practically
anything: web pages,
presentations, dashboards,
interactives, applications, even
games—whatever you want.  Come on.  And I
know that you know that Canvas exists and you've
probably used it before
, but I'm sure you're not
yet aware of everything you can
do with Canvas.  And in this video I'm going to
show you not one, not two, not three, but
nine amazing things you can
do with Canvas.  But before that, you know
I'd really appreciate it if you gave it a
like and subscribed to the channel if you haven't already
.  And by the way, something very
important, all the prompts and all the
examples that we are going to see in this video
can be found in the link that I
leave you in the description.  It's completely
free, you just have to follow the
steps.  And now let's get down to business.  Before we
begin, I assume everyone has
used Gemini's canvas option at some point
, but for those who are
a bit behind the times
, we simply need to go
to the tools option and
select the canvas tool, and that's it
, it's now activated.
Importantly, this tool is available
in both the free and
pro accounts.  You'll see that I use the pro account
because that's where I have all the
examples, but you can use it without
any problem on the free account,
obviously with certain limitations.  Okay,
let's go with the first use case, which has only recently
come to light:
Yemini is becoming increasingly interactive.
This is no longer
just about receiving plain text responses; now it
allows us to do things like
simulations or create
interactive models.  This helps you visualize
concepts or ideas much better and
understand them much better.  Let's suppose we
are explaining
the orbit of the Moon to a friend and that person doesn't
understand it.  No matter how much you
explain it to him, he doesn't understand.  Well, with
Gemini you can exemplify it in a
very didactic and also
interactive way.  We simply have to
tell him something like this.  Create a simulation of
the moon's orbit and voilà!  We would already
have our simulation or our
interactive model.  Now here we
can, for example, adjust the
speed of time.  You'll see that it keeps
spinning faster and faster, and here
the moon appears, moving too fast.
We paused the simulation.  The good thing about this
is that it usually allows us to
do it in a very interactive way.
Notice that I can move and
completely rotate this model, which in this
case is the Earth or rather the
orbit of the Moon.  Or for example, here we
ask you to do a simulation of
fractal growth so that we can
easily see how this process works.
Here we can select, for example,
the number of iterations and the
branching angle.  Look how cool it is!  Oh, and
then the length ratio,
lower, higher, 10 iterations and 20 gr
of branching.  Look how nice
this looks.  If you have to explain it to
someone in your own words, well,
maybe they won't understand.  And with this
you can understand it in a moment.  Just
look how cool this is.  This is for teaching
classes and things like that.  The truth is, it's really
cool, huh?  Now let's look at another
use case that I think makes the
difference between using canvas and not
using it, even if it's only for
working with plain text.  For example, in a
real-world case, let's say I need to create
a five-email email marketing campaign
to sell my private
inertia community about
artificial intelligence; I could perfectly use
Gemini's canvas tool.  And now I'll explain how.
Look, I'm asking for plain text, but
I'm selecting the canvas option.  And
obviously, the ideal thing to do here is to use
reasoning mode or pro mode,
okay?  Especially if we are going to
do coding tasks or even
search and analysis tasks.  In this case,
we're going to use the pro option.
Look, here we see the result we
requested, but it doesn't give us the
answer with the typical chat.
Obviously, it opens the
canvas window and in this case generates the
text inside the canvas.  The good thing about this
case is the option to create.  Look,
here we have the five emails we
asked for.  Here I can go
to the create tab and ask it to make me
, for example, a website, an
infographic, a quiz, or flashcards
.  This is very useful if we have to
study a topic, present it, and
so on.  We can even make an
audio summary.  The good thing about this
is that I can select
any text here and ask Gemini
, "Give me an example of this."  And
not only does he give us an example, but he
explains it to us with this long paragraph, and that way we
can ask him anything
interactively and very quickly.
We want to change this title,
so we ask you to.  Change this title, it's
too clickbait.  Tachan and changes it.   It's that
easy to ask if we don't like something or
even want to shorten or lengthen it
,
okay?  We can go to any paragraph you
want, or we can go to any part
of the text and ask you to make the
necessary changes.  As I mentioned, this is
a new way of working within
Yemy Knight, and it will increasingly
allow us to interact more
directly with the work we
are doing.  You won't need to
be copying and pasting all the time anymore.  And
by the way, speaking of copy and paste,
the following case is something that will
blow your mind, especially for those
people who want to create their own
website or rather want to have
a great website.  All
we have to do is use
canvas mode.  As I'm about to explain
, for all of you who want to
create an amazing website, this
process is going to blow your mind.  Look,
let's suppose we want to create a design
like this web page here, the
mobing page.  This is a design that I
personally like a lot.  So,
normally, what would I do,
which we've done in other videos?  So what we would do is
make this small
or take several screenshots and then paste
those screenshots into the chat and
explain that we want to make a
similar website.  But my friend,
this is over now.  Now we can record
the screen, which is what I've done.   I
made this video here portraying
the entire Mobin homepage.  And look, it's
a really
cool website.  The question is, will the
Canvas tool be able to create a page
like Mobin's?  Let's take a look.   We
simply send him the video and then
write him the prompt.  Act like an
expert frontend developer.
Carefully analyze the attached video where
I show the website.  Your task is to
recreate the website with the greatest
possible visual and functional accuracy.
Notice that we have
pro mode selected here and now, pay attention, we have to
select the canvas tool.
Let's see.  which makes us.  Well, I've
already done it.  Look, patapam.  Take.  It's a
joke.  This is the real one.  Let's
see the clone.  Now, ladies and
gentlemen, take a look at the amazing website he's
created for us.  Look at this!
Obviously, not all
effects are included.  We would have to iterate this
a little bit ourselves, but notice that it
has created the entire structure and all the
HTML for us.  Yes, it is true that, well, we would have to
specify this a
little more, especially regarding
the transitions, effects,
animations, and so on.  But look at this amazing
website!  We simply
recorded his screen and
told him to copy it, and that's it.  And here,
obviously, I wanted to use an
example that is a little more difficult,
okay?  I could have used, for
example, let's say a more
static website, and it would have been
much easier, but I wanted to
take it a step further and the truth is that it's not
bad at all.  In fact, you can see here how I
did it.  I simply
asked him about the prompt and he hasn't even tried it once
.  So, this is the first
version he's created for me, and the best part
is that he created it in HTML and
CSS, well, in Tailwin CSS.  And that's possibly why it does
n't look so much like it.
Now, as you know,
we could iterate within Canvas and
start modifying our website or
start destroying it, okay?  In other words, it's up to
you.
[laughs]
The truth is, this
website we made
in less than a minute isn't bad at all.  And since we already have
a website, now we just need a game; we
can also ask him to make us a
completely interactive game.  Look,
here I've simply asked him to
program a typing survival game
where
the words fall from the sky and you
have to type faster and
faster.  By the way, spoiler alert, it
's not for the faint of heart.  Okay, let's go
.  game, game.  Okay.
Oh, the truth is that in the end things have gotten
complicated and like this game, we can
play almost any
browser game, that is, any game that allows us
to interact within the browser.  In
fact, some people have created a
Minecraft, we even created
a flight simulator ourselves, I don't know if you
remember, but we created an MVP for a
role-playing game, a shooter, and so on.
Okay, so, you can do a lot of
things, even things that
we could integrate into our
website or application,
tools, calculators, and so on.
Now let's look at a
slightly more practical use case that solves
real problems.  Let's suppose we are
a financial disaster.  It's just
a guess, don't take it the
wrong way, but if we find it hard to save or to keep track of
our personal finances,
the canvas tool could
help us create our own
financial dashboard.  Look, the first thing I did here
was send him a fake bank statement
, okay?  And so I asked him to
turn that bank statement
into an interactive personal finance dashboard
.  And look what a cool thing he's
created for me.  We have the current balance, the
income, the expenses for this month,
we can add transactions, whether
expenses or income, organize it by
category, by date, well,
impressive.  And then, we can see
where our money is really going.
income, monthly payroll, expenses,
well, all of these and we could have a
financial summary that would even allow us to
save a little more.
Let's move on to the next use case.
Now we're going to solve another problem
that you might also have at
home.  Imagine that your
food always spoils in the fridge and you don't
know what to do anymore.  You've tried to
organize yourself in every way
possible, well,
you can also solve this
problem with the canvas tool.  For example, we can tell him to
create a pantry-type application.
You enter the ingredients and the
expiration date, and the application
generates real-time recipes with what
is about to expire.  That's exactly what
we've done.  Look, to do
this I admit we used a
slightly longer prompt, but
hey, if you want to see this prompt, you can
find it in the collection
of prompts linked in the
description.  So, we've
put all this text here to generate
our pantry application.  Notice
that if I put here, for example, milk
and that it expires on April 15th of this year,
notice that it already appears here that it expires
tomorrow.  So, we can go to the life
preserver option and generate the
recipe for making use of the leftovers.  Patapam
spinach lifesaving scramble.  Sauté
spinach with tomatoes, milk and
add a couple of beaten eggs for a quick and
nutritious meal.  What a Molotov cocktail, but oh
well, it might be okay.
Leftover cream.  Boil spinach with a
little broth or water.  Blend and add
a splash of cream or milk.  Perfect
for dinner.  Well, it's about
spinach.  And here we can make the
shopping list.  In fact, I'm thinking
this app would be
perfect for us at home.  And the good thing about this
is that we can extrapolate this to
any other area, to any other
need we may have, whether
at work or also in our
homes on a personal level.  The truth is,
the dashboard was pretty cool.  Okay, like I
said, if you want the prompt, I'll leave it
in the description.  Now we're going to do
an example very similar to the one we
saw at the beginning, but we're going to
use the create option so
you can see all the options you can
use if you have to study or
present anything.  Look,
let's say we're studying
black holes and we need our
ultimate study kit, well, we
could do this with
Canvas too.  We have this entire syllabus
here which, as you can see, is quite
extensive.  And now we could click the
create button and ask it to make some
flashcards or even an
infographic.  But anyway, in this case
we're going to ask him to make us those
flashcards that will help us
study in a much more
interactive way than simply reading.
Now we're going to study in an
interactive way.  Black hole.  Let's go.
Region of space with an immense
amount of concentrated matter and
gravity so strong that not even light can
escape.  Holy [ __ ], that's a bad vibe.
Singularity, I know this one.
Central point of a black hole of
zero volume and infinite density where the laws
of physics cease to function.  Well, that
wasn't it.  [laughs]
And here we would have 25 cards to
study in a slightly
more interactive way.  Anyway, if
we go back to the study kit, we can
ask it to also print out an
infographic for us.  That is, you can't
imagine how many times I've created
infographics to make presentations,
explain things, or even use them
as material for a meeting.  These
kinds of things ultimately help us, but
only if we know how to do them.  And in
this case it's very easy, you just have to
press this button which is a
little hidden.  Why
kid ourselves?  Notice that he's already making
this infographic for me.  He will create the
structure in HTML code as
usual and then the styles in CSS.  And here it is
.  Just so
you know, you can open this in
any browser, as it's in
HTML code.  You can simply copy
all the code, take it wherever you want,
and then just open it
in any browser and it will work.  We would then
have our presentation or
infographic of the syllabus or
document that you want.  And look at this amazing
infographic!  It's not
bad at all.  In fact, this is usually going to be
much better than practically
any material you prepare.  So now you
know.  Look at what we
were talking about earlier, about simulations and
interactive models.  I mean, if you show this
to a client, a
student, or your teacher, they'll be blown away
.  Everyone who lands here
will want to interact with the mouse and see
how it works.  It's almost impossible, isn't it?
Turn it and play around with the mouse a bit
.  Now let's move on to what I call
the ultimate combo, Yemini and Notebook LM.
The integration of
these two Google tools has already been discussed, but
with Canvas we can do something much more
powerful.  Look, let's suppose we're
planning a trip to Japan and,
because we're very clever, we use
a tool like Notebook LM that
allows us to extract the maximum amount of information from
the sources we want.  In
this case, I have used several sources
of interest to prepare, for example,
a trip to Japan, and these are the
sources here.  Right now, what
I can do once I have the notebook
created is go back to Gemini and
ask it to do the following.  We
can tell you to create an
interactive website for a 14-day trip that
is navigable with menus organizing the
cities, monuments and maps
based on the researched
notebook documents.  LM.  And now we have to do
something very important.  We're going to
files and instead of having to upload
our files or
links ourselves, we're going to go directly to
notebook LM.  We're going to select the
notebook, which in this case is Essential
Japan Travel Guide, and add it
as a source of information.  Now we'll
be working with that board.  There's no
need to copy and paste like crazy.
We simply have to select the
canvas option, verify that we have
the mode we are interested in, and see what it will
do to us.  He created another amazing
website for us, planning our 14-
day trip to Japan, starting with the
first day and ending with the last, which
would be in Osaka.  Notice that I have
n't had to iterate even once here.  And
here it gives you the itinerary, guide and
labels and the news for 2026,
changes in tax free, openings of the
pokepark, teamlab, etc.  Okay, in the
practical guide and etiquette, we'll cover what you
need to know before boarding the
plane, tips based on
local culture to avoid standing out on your trip and making a big mess of things
.  Here you would find
a series of tips, but what
interests us is the itinerary.  Notice here
that we have selected the
first day and now if we scroll down a little,
the itinerary for the first day appears, which
would be arrival and neon lights.  Arrival
at Kansai Airport.  Immerse yourself in
otaku culture at Dendentone.  Savor the
street food at
Kuromon Market and marvel at the neon lights of
Dotonbor at night.  The truth is that it's
quite comprehensive.  What to see and what to do?
So look, here's a summary:
Doton Bory, Dendentone and
Kuromon Market.  And so we could see what
each day holds for us.  Day 2 was
quite full, day 3 too, and so on
every day.  If you manage to reach the
14th, then you'll go back home, but not
before saying goodbye and doing some
last shopping.  The truth is, it
's not bad at all.  You could do this on
one of your trips or even at any
event you organize.  I think these
things are invaluable and
really useful.  And now let's move on to the
last case.  I've left it for last
because it's, let's say, a little bit more
technical.  And be careful, because what I'm going to
show you now is one of the secrets that
some programmers use to
solve some code problems, and
obviously it's with the
canvas function, and it's very similar to what we've
seen before, but it's not the same.
Look, here we've asked him to
help us with a script, which in this
case is a script to automate
a filter in Gmail.  Well, basically it's to
automatically reply to
some emails that arrive in my inbox
.  So, here
we could test it, and we
could also go to a piece of code,
select it and say, explain to me what
this does.  And in this way we could
solve many of the problems that
our scripts sometimes give us,
especially when we are working
with languages ​​that we don't normally
use.  And here it explains
exactly what the piece
of code you have underlined is and what it does.  And in
fact, it gives you a
complete explanation and a summary.  But the good thing about
this is that here I can tell it, for
example, I underline everything, right-click
and say, "Find me the errors or
possible improvements in the code."  Patapam.
And now he reviews the code for you and
explains that we could apply the
following improvements directly to the
document.  And here he gives us a list of
these things that we could improve.  The
good thing about this is that we don't have to
change everything or copy and paste it into
the typical artificial intelligence model
and ask it to improve it, but instead
we can go to the
exact section where we want,
for example, this one here, and ask it to
redo it or ask it to extend it,
ask it to fix it, whatever we
want.  And that's where the magic
of the canvas tool for
viipe coding lies.  This is an
impressive tool, especially for
getting started with Vipe Coding, which, if you do
n't know, is developing
software by leveraging
artificial intelligence.  And by the way, now that
the topic of viipe coding has come up, if you're interested in
learning more about it and want to know how to
use artificial intelligence like
a true professional, you should
join my private
Inertia community, where you'll become a
genuine
AI professional.  I'll leave the link below in
the description.  And that's it, after the
ad I'll say goodbye, but not before
reminding you that you also have all the prompts
below in the description and they are
totally free.  Not only these
prompts and examples, but all the
examples and all the prompts that we have
seen throughout the channel.  So
, there you have it, see you in the
next video.